[Music]
[音乐]
hi everyone thanks for coming out this
大家好，谢谢您的参与
is a packed house thank you so much for
是一个拥挤的房子，非常感谢
coming up to my talk and really
来我的演讲，真的
appreciate the organizers sorry for
感谢主办方对不起
allowing me come here 30 or in a row I
请允许我30或连续来到这里
love Barcelona happy to be back my name
爱巴萨快乐回到我的名字
is Joel Grande I'm on a spring security
是乔尔·格兰德（Joel Grande），我要参加春季安全检查
team mainly focused on the new OAuth
团队主要致力于新的OAuth
support that we're building in spring
支持我们在春季建造
security 500 US Open ID Connect Jose
安全500美国公开赛ID连接Jose
framework support and so forth it's been
框架支持等等
a it's been it's been like about three
大概是三个
years now or two and a half years that
几年或两年半的时间
we've undertaken this rewrite of the new
我们已经对新的
Ola support spring security five and as
奥拉支持春季安全五和
probably most of you are aware there is
也许你们大多数人都知道
an existing project spring security
现有的项目春季安全
OAuth we call it legacy oh ah right now
OAuth，我们称它为传统哦
it's in maintenance mode it's been
处于维护模式
around for about seven years it's gonna
大约七年
eventually retire that's why we're doing
最终退休，这就是我们要做的原因
this rewrites five two is coming out in
这重写了五个两个即将推出
August and at that point we're gonna be
八月，那时我们将成为
a feature parity with client and
与客户端的功能均等
resource service it's gonna be a huge
资源服务将是巨大的
milestone for us and we're hoping
我们的里程碑，我们希望
everyone's gonna migrate to the new
每个人都将迁移到新
stuff we're going to provide a migration
我们将提供迁移的东西
path and everything so today I'm gonna
道路和一切，所以今天我要
be talking about that and you know the
谈论这个，你知道
implementations within Spring security
Spring安全性内的实现
five and five one of the of the security
证券的五分之一和五分之一
standards that we've implemented so I'm
我们已经实施的标准
gonna be demonstrating I mean I got a
会表明我的意思是我得到了
couple of slides here I'm basically I
我基本上是几张幻灯片
got a demo and instead of doing a simple
有一个演示，而不是做一个简单的
demo you know off to login or setting up
您知道要登录或设置的演示
a resource server I get a lot of
我得到很多资源服务器
questions how you piece everything
质疑您如何拼凑一切
together right where you have a lot of
在一起，在那里你有很多
different components like let's say a
比如说一个不同的组件
micro services architecture you got
您拥有的微服务架构
multiple services how do you communicate
多种服务，您如何沟通
between each of the services what token
每个服务之间有什么令牌
do you obtain what authorization granted
您获得了什么授权
you obtain to call this one service and
您可以致电此一项服务，并且
so forth so how do you piece it all
如此等等，你怎么把这一切
together so that's what I'm going to be
在一起，这就是我要做的
going through a more advanced sample
通过更高级的样本
with three micro sources that's gonna be
有三个微观来源
on the next slide but I'm gonna give a
在下一张幻灯片上，但我要给
really high level of the standards that
真正高水平的标准
we've implemented so far in spring
到目前为止，我们已经在春季实施了
security five up to five one and five to
安全五至五一和五至
let me just get a raise of hands I want
让我举手
to understand
了解
who's who's very familiar with OAuth
谁是对OAuth非常熟悉的人
here okay perfect who's used the spring
好的，这是谁的春天
security support five one five two
安全支持五一五二
oauth2 logins resource server who's
oauth2登录谁的资源服务器
using the legacy auth okay that's good
使用旧版身份验证还可以
they'll be easy to use the new stuff so
他们将很容易使用新的东西，所以
I'll just I'll just give a really quick
我就给我一个非常快的
high-level overview and we'll just jump
高层次的概述，我们将跳转
into the demo and and and putting it
进入演示，然后放入
together
一起
Oh auth - authorization framework I mean
哦auth-我的意思是授权框架
this is all about authorization it's all
这就是授权的全部
about authorizing a third-party
关于授权第三方
application and ooofff client and OAuth
应用程序和ooofff客户端以及OAuth
application whatever you want to call it
您想调用它的应用程序
authorize it to access your protected
授权它访问您的受保护
resources right you know your typical
你知道你的典型资源
use cases log in with Google login with
用例使用Google登录名登录
octa right that's your typical use case
八位权利是您的典型用例
the one you the one you guys all know
你们一个人你们都知道
right and girls and you know you go you
对，女孩，你知道你去了
click on it you go to a website you
点击它，你去一个网站你
click on log in with Google and you get
点击使用Google登录，您将获得
redirected to Google you log in and then
重定向到您登录的Google，然后
you get this consent screen do you
你会得到这个同意屏幕吗
authorize this application to access
授权此应用程序访问
your protected resources specifically
专门保护您的资源
your user info or your email address and
您的用户信息或电子邮件地址，以及
so forth you click on authorize you've
依此类推，您点击授权
just authorized this client in the
刚刚在
background the client gets this
客户得到这个背景
authorization code or an authorization
授权码或授权
grant typically an authorization code if
通常授予以下授权码：
it's dollarization code grant that is
这是美元化代码授予
and it exchanges for an access token a
并交换访问令牌a
short-lived credential that has the
具有以下条件的短期凭证
capabilities to access your user profile
可以访问您的用户个人资料
information right so all about
正确的信息就这样
authorization off to authorization
授权转授权
framework it only deals with
它只处理的框架
authorization open ID Connect that's
授权开放ID Connect
where authentication comes in it's built
内置身份验证的地方
on top of OAuth 2 and you know leverages
在OAuth 2之上，您知道杠杆
the grant types the authorization code
授予类型授权码
but it introduces the ID token right
但它引入了ID令牌权限
instead of an authorization request
代替授权请求
it's an authentication request right but
这是身份验证请求，但是
it leverages the authorization code but
它利用授权码，但是
when it hits the token endpoint on top
当它到达顶部的令牌端点时
of the access token it also gets this ID
的访问令牌也将获得此ID
token right and this ID token has a set
令牌权限，此ID令牌有一个
of claims in there that describe the
那里描述的索赔
authenticated user at the provider first
首先在提供者处通过身份验证的用户
name last name subject issuer and so
名字姓氏主题颁发者等
forth and we're gonna take a look at
来，我们来看看
that as we as we go through the demo
当我们进行演示时
open ID connect discovery open ID
打开ID连接发现打开ID
connect providers may may implement this
连接提供商可以实现此目的
endpoint where clients or resource
客户端或资源所在的端点
servers can discover provider metadata
服务器可以发现提供者元数据
for example discover the authorization
例如发现授权
endpoint token endpoint user info
端点令牌端点用户信息
endpoint etc so I'm gonna I'm going to
端点等，所以我要去
show you an example of that as we're
向我们展示一个例子
going through the demo GWT
通过演示GWT
self-contained type of access token you
您自己的访问令牌类型
got also opaque tokens GWT I mean
也有不透明的令牌GWT我的意思是
self-contained all the attributes are in
自包含所有属性
the jwk sets so it's pretty convenient
jwk设置，因此非常方便
for resource servers to receive a GWT
资源服务器接收GWT
decode it and make an authorization
对其进行解码并进行授权
decision opaque tokens on the other hand
另一方面，决策不透明令牌
and that's coming on five - by the way
顺便说一句五点
opaque tokens support it's it's it's
不透明的令牌支持它是
opaque it's you can't deduce anything
不透明的是你不能演绎任何东西
out of it it's it's a unique identifier
它是唯一的标识符
and the only way the resource server can
并且资源服务器可以的唯一方法
get attributes associated to that access
获取与该访问关联的属性
token it has to call the introspection
令牌，它必须调用内省
endpoint so it's an extra request
端点，所以这是一个额外的请求
response call obviously it reduces
响应电话明显减少了
scalability in that respect but at the
在这方面的可扩展性，但在
same time there's pros and cons to
同时有利弊
self-contained token and opaque token
自包含令牌和不透明令牌
I'm not going to get into all that right
我不会全力以赴
now but there you go JWT and then GWS I
现在，但是您去了JWT，然后是GWS I
mean JW T's can't be signed an ID token
表示无法为JW T签名ID令牌
is signed and hopefully any every GWT
已签署，希望每一个GWT
you signed at the very minimum you
你至少签了名
definitely do not want to be using
绝对不想被使用
unsecure JWT s for sure so that's GWS
肯定是不安全的JWT，所以这就是GWS
and then you got jwe java web json web
然后你得到jwe java web json web
encryption which is part of the whole
加密是整体的一部分
Jose framework which is JSON object
Jose框架是JSON对象
signing and encryption right and then we
签名和加密，然后我们
have the gwk JSON web key so that's a
有gwk JSON Web密钥，所以这是一个
that's a JSON representation of a public
这是公众的JSON表示形式
key or a key right it could be a
关键或关键权利可能是
symmetric key like a shared key or a
对称密钥，例如共享密钥或
symmetric key like an RSA key that's
对称密钥，例如RSA密钥
ultimately used by the provider to sign
最终由提供者用来签署
the JWT and the resource server or the
JWT和资源服务器或
client in the open ID Connect
客户端打开ID连接
side of things needs that key to verify
事物的一面需要那个钥匙来验证
the signature right so there's there's a
签名正确，所以有一个
from a very very high level the the
从非常高的水平
standards that have been implemented in
已实施的标准
spring security 5 and I'm going to show
春季安全5，我将展示
you how we're leveraging it this in this
您如何在此方面利用它
right from a high level I'm just gonna
从高层次来看，我只是
go over this is what we're gonna do and
过去，这就是我们要做的，
there's a lot to do and I'm gonna try to
有很多事情要做，我将尝试
get this in without rushing and you know
不用急于得到它，你知道
kind of having a whirlwind of a demo I'm
有点像演示的旋风
gonna do my best to like really pace it
要尽我所能去喜欢真正的节奏
but get all of this done because this is
但这要做好，因为这是
our goal is this is our architecture
我们的目标是这是我们的架构
we've got three micro-services we got a
我们有三个微服务，我们有一个
UI app and an authorization server the
UI应用程序和授权服务器
UI app right acts as you know an api
UI应用程序权限就像您了解API一样
gateway or a back-end forefront and that
网关或后端最前端
pattern if you know that all requests
模式，如果您知道所有请求
funnel through the UI app the client is
通过客户端的UI应用程序进行渠道
a browser or a native mobile app
浏览器或本机移动应用
whatever right but all the requests go
任何权利，但所有请求都去了
through there provides a coarse-grained
通过那里提供了一个粗粒度
api
api
and ultimately it aggregates or calls
最终聚集或调用
the micro services the finer grained
微服务更细粒度
api's and aggregates the response back
api并将响应汇总回去
to the client right so the UI app here
向客户的权利，因此UI应用程序在这里
basic finally fapla keishon this is a
基本的最后fapla keishon这是一个
perfect perfect spot to you know set up
您知道的完美地点
open ID open ID connect the
打开ID打开ID连接
authentication like this is where
像这样的身份验证
cross-cutting concerns can happen you
横切关注点可能会发生
can even set up authorization here
甚至可以在这里设置授权
routing whatever but the api gateway
路由除api网关外的任何路由
pattern it's a well-known pattern best
模式，这是最有名的模式
practice for sure then we got these
肯定地练习，然后我们得到了这些
three micro services right so the UI app
三个微服务对，所以UI应用程序
is gonna call micro service a micro
将微服务称为微服务
service be so we're also gonna set up an
服务是这样，我们也将建立一个
OAuth client there as a second step
第二步是OAuth客户端
that's going to ultimately go through
最终将要经历
the authorization code grant flow to get
获得授权码的流程
an access token then pass it to micro
访问令牌，然后将其传递给micro
service a micro service be micro service
服务微服务是微服务
B we're gonna set up a row OAuth client
B我们要设置一个OAuth客户端行
there with the client credentials grant
那里有客户凭证授予
and I explained you you know what cases
我告诉你你知道什么情况
do you use client credentials grant
您是否使用客户端凭据授予
compared to authorization code when you
与授权码相比
get to that we're gonna set that up
到那我们要设置
there and it's gonna it's gonna call
在那里，它将要打电话
micro service C so that's what we're
微服务C，这就是我们
gonna do so let's just get to it right
我们要做的就是正确地做
now so let's uh let's jump to the demo
现在，让我们来跳到演示
here I'm just going to show you actually
在这里，我实际上将向您展示
so this this this this sample app I got
所以这是我得到的这个示例应用
a few different flows here the whole
整个这里有一些不同的流程
goal my whole goal anyways of this app
无论如何，我的目标都是我的目标
is to demonstrate flows right and best
是为了展示正确和最佳的流程
practices you know as far as patterns go
就模式而言，您知道的实践
you know like
你知道像
here I got five different flows they
在这里我有五种不同的流程
have very simple flows there then I got
有非常简单的流程，然后我得到了
a token relay pattern token exchange I
令牌中继模式令牌交换I
can't I can't demonstrate all that we're
我不能证明我们所有的一切
just gonna focus on the bottom on the
只是要专注于底部
client credentials flow but my hope the
客户凭证流，但我希望
whole goal of this app is to have
这个程序的整体目标是
something more advanced rate a more
更高级的东西
advanced architecture that you know has
您知道的高级架构
security implemented as far as you know
据您所知实施的安全性
spring security fives OAuth and open ID
Spring Security Fives OAuth和开放ID
connect support so people could go to
连接支持，以便人们可以去
this check it out learn from it and just
这个检查出来从中学习，只是
learn best practices right and I don't
正确学习最佳做法，我却没有
have a domain model built into this
有一个内置的领域模型
because domain model is just gonna be
因为领域模型将成为
noise right this is all about
噪音对不对
interactions between services and what
服务与什么之间的交互
access tokens flow between each services
访问令牌在每个服务之间流动
so I'm literally displaying like a click
所以我的意思是像点击一样显示
on this flow as you can see there's a
在此流程上，您可以看到有一个
flow sequence there and then I got some
那里的流程顺序，然后我得到了一些
metadata right between each of the each
每个元数据之间的元数据
of the interactions between the
之间的相互作用
components UI app call service say
组件UI应用程序调用服务说
there's no data there now but this is
现在没有数据，但这是
gonna get populated as we're you know
就像我们知道的那样会人口稠密
securing the application right but
确保申请权，但
you've got a GTI there that's basically
你有一个GTI，基本上
the JSON identifier so we'll see what
JSON标识符，所以我们将看到
access token is being passed authorities
访问令牌正在通过授权
so maybe you know authority like
所以也许你知道权威
information like scopes and so forth so
诸如范围之类的信息等等
uh so let's get to it let's set out
嗯，让我们开始吧，出发
let's do our first first part of the
让我们做第一部分的
demo is we're gonna set up open ID
演示是我们要设置开放ID
authentication with the UI app what does
使用UI应用程序进行身份验证
that take now the first thing we got to
现在我们要做的第一件事
do just these are all spring boot apps
只是这些都是 spring boot 应用程序
so the first thing we got to do is add
所以我们要做的第一件事就是添加
the dependencies right I'm gonna make
我要建立的依赖关系
this a little bit bigger so everyone can
这个更大一点，所以每个人都可以
see so the two dependencies required for
看到所以两个所需的依赖
oauth2 client is obviously the spring
oauth2客户端显然是春天
boot starter security starter and the
开机启动程序安全启动程序和
oauth2 client starter those are the two
oauth2客户端启动器是两个
starters done right so I had those first
入门者做对了，所以我有了第一个
and then the second thing now I'm going
然后第二件事我要走了
to actually remove
实际删除
I've actually disabled security as you
我实际上已经禁用了您的安全性
saw I went into the application identic
看到我进入了相同的应用程序
8 and you know I just got in right so
8，你知道我刚刚说对了
I've disabled everything by excluding
我已经通过排除禁用所有内容
the auto configuration for boot so I'm
开机自动配置，所以我
going to remove that right now and now
现在要立即删除
we're gonna go into
我们要去
the application properties and we're
应用程序属性，我们
gonna add the properties for the client
将为客户端添加属性
rate for the clients I'm gonna go over
为我要去的客户评分
these a bit the key properties here so
这些都是这里的关键特性
spring spring security oauth2 client
Spring Spring Security OAuth2客户端
that's the base property path right
那是基础属性路径
below that we have registration and but
下面我们有注册，但是
at that level and providers so
在那个级别上，提供商
registration is you could you could
注册是您可以的
register more than one clients right
注册多个客户权利
because you can use a client like this
因为你可以使用这样的客户
client here is used for my open ID
这里的客户端用于我的开放ID
connected n occation right I can use
我可以使用的连接位置
another client for the authorization
另一个授权客户
code which I'm going to demonstrate as
我将要演示的代码
we progress but I could add me as many
我们进步了，但我可以加我很多
clients as I want depending what this
我想要的客户取决于这
app needs right and then provider is the
应用程序需要权利，然后提供商是
provider metadata obviously I got to
提供者元数据显然我要
know the authorization endpoint token
知道授权端点令牌
endpoint user info endpoints so that's
端点用户信息端点，因此
so I could set up multiple providers so
所以我可以设置多个提供商
technically I could set up anything here
从技术上讲，我可以在这里设置任何东西
I could set up Google octa UA a have
我可以设置Google octa UA
multiple clients and so forth right now
现在有多个客户，依此类推
right below the registration this is the
在注册下方，这是
registration ID it's just the logical
注册ID，这只是合乎逻辑的
name I could I've could have given it
我可以给的名字
any name whatsoever it's just got to be
任何名称，只要有
unique within the client registration or
在客户注册中是唯一的，或者
posit or e but the key thing here I
posit或e但关键在这里
wanted to point out is a scope open ID
要指出的是范围开放ID
that's a required scope for Open ID
这是Open ID的必需范围
Connect that's what triggers an
连接才是触发
authentication request if I removed open
身份验证请求，如果我删除了open
ID even though it's using authorization
ID（即使正在使用授权）
code it just falls back to the
代码，它只是回到
authorization code grant standard oauth2
授权码授予标准oauth2
so open ID is the indicator this is an
因此，开放ID是一个指标
authentication request so that's so you
身份验证请求，这样您就可以
got to make sure you add that for open
必须确保您将其添加为开放
ID connect and then the redirect URI
标识连接，然后重定向URI
this is the default default redirect URI
这是默认的默认重定向URI
where when I login I authorize the
登录时我授权
client to access my user information and
客户访问我的用户信息，以及
then the authorization server redirects
然后授权服务器重定向
the authorization grant in this case is
在这种情况下，授权授权为
the authorization code back to the
授权码回到
redirect here I back to the application
重定向到这里我回到应用程序
client receives it exchanges for an
客户收到它交换
access token alright and then we have
访问令牌好，然后我们有
the provider information right
提供者信息权
authorization token user influence so
授权令牌用户的影响如此
forth
向前
so that's it so that's what I did right
就是这样，这就是我做的正确的
I basically add
我基本上添加
like dependencies add in my properties
像依赖项一样添加到我的属性中
now let's let's see what happens I'm
现在让我们看看我发生了什么
gonna restart the application and then
要重新启动应用程序，然后
we're gonna see what happens here okay
我们要看看这里会发生什么
this is good right so we got redirected
这很好，所以我们被重定向了
back to to our authorization server
回到我们的授权服务器
which I'm actually using UAA for from my
我实际上是在使用UAA
authorization server for either for
的授权服务器
those of you who don't know you a is
那些不认识你的人是
cloud Foundry's identity management
cloud Foundry的身份管理
system so I'm using that running that
系统，所以我正在使用该
locally so I get this message here do
在本地，所以我在这里收到此消息
you know typical message that you get if
您知道如果收到的典型消息
you're logging in with Google or if do
您正在使用Google登录，或者
you authorize Google or the authorize
您授权Google或授权
this application or this client to
此应用程序或此客户端
access my user information email address
访问我的用户信息电子邮件地址
profile and so forth so I'm gonna click
个人资料等等，所以我要点击
on authorize and there you go so now I
在授权上，你去了，所以现在我
see extra information right I've Athena
我在雅典娜那里看到更多信息
cated right I got my name up but the top
没错，我叫我名字，但最重要的是
right there I have this link that
就在那里，我有这个链接
displays some information like I was
显示一些信息，就像我以前
talking about earlier
较早谈论
excuse me like I was talking about
对不起，就像我在说
earlier the the ID token comes back on a
之前ID令牌返回到
token endpoint on an open ID connect
开放ID连接上的令牌端点
flow and we have claims in the ID token
流程，我们在ID令牌中有声明
here are the claims here some of the the
这是这里的一些要求
the there's more claims but these are
还有更多的要求，但这些是
some of them claims I'm just displaying
他们中有些人声称我只是在展示
here right now obviously the two key
现在在这里显然是两个关键
ones are issuer and subject so issuer
既是发行人又是发行人，所以发行人
that unique identify or the provider and
该唯一标识或提供者，以及
then subject the unique identifier of me
然后以我的唯一标识符为准
at the provider and the combination of
在提供者处以及
those two is basically a global unique
这两个基本上是全球唯一的
identifier of a user out of provider and
提供者之外的用户的标识符，以及
then we have you know a few different
那我们就知道一些不同
claims you know the my name first name
声称您知道我的名字名字
last name email and so forth authorized
姓氏电子邮件等已获授权
party the audience who's the audience of
参加听众聚会
this of this ID token obviously it's the
这个ID令牌显然是
clients and then I have some information
客户，然后我有一些信息
here you know as far as the clients that
在这里，您对客户知道
have been registered I could look at the
已经注册了，我可以看看
access token I got the ID token you know
访问令牌，我得到了您知道的ID令牌
this information here like I said this
这些信息就像我说的
this app is more of a best practices in
这个应用程式更像是最佳做法
learning what happens between the flows
了解流之间发生了什么
and what's happening in a session just
以及会议中发生的事情
viewing the information seen just
查看刚刚看到的信息
introspecting within
内省
within the application the you know
在应用程序中，您知道
what's happening as far as you know when
据您所知，发生了什么事
security is enabled here with OAuth so
通过OAuth在此处启用了安全性，因此
there you go so so I got open ID
你去了，所以我得到了开放的ID
connected indication implement that was
已连接的指示工具
pretty easy I had my dependencies
很容易，我有了依赖
I had my properties and I'm done right
我拥有财产，做对了
easy well I find it easy anyways
好吧，我还是觉得很容易
hopefully you do too
希望你也这样做
now I'm looking at this though and you
现在我正在看这个，而你
know there's a few properties here you
知道这里有一些属性
know I like to make this a little bit
知道我喜欢做一点
smaller make it like make it even easier
更小使其更容易
right so what can I do
对，那我该怎么办
I could leverage open ID connect
我可以利用开放ID连接
discovery
发现
all right so open ID connect providers
好的，所以开放ID连接提供商
can implement this endpoint and they
可以实现这个端点，他们
expose provider metadata so as you can
公开提供程序元数据，以便您可以
see here I got the authorization
看到这里我得到了授权
endpoint token endpoint I mean there's
端点令牌端点，我的意思是
quite a few things here that providers
提供者在这里有很多东西
can't expose and in basically clients or
不能公开，基本上在客户或
resource servers can call the discovery
资源服务器可以调用发现
endpoint and ultimately use this data
端点并最终使用此数据
for example a client could look up the
例如，客户可以查找
discovery endpoint and automatically
自动发现端点
configure itself with a few different of
用一些不同的配置自己
these pieces of information so let's try
这些信息，让我们尝试
that let's try let's try the the open ID
让我们尝试让我们尝试打开ID
Connect discovery integration with
将发现集成与
spring security and make make our client
春季安全，使我们的客户
registration even simpler so what I'm
注册更简单，所以我
going to do is I'm gonna get rid of all
我要做的就是摆脱一切
this stuff right on the provider I'm
这些东西就在我
just gonna add the issuer URI and I
只需添加发行者URI，我
already know by default these two are
默认已经知道这两个是
defaulted the authorization code and
默认授权码和
redirect URI so that's that's a lot
重定向URI，这就是很多
easier right I mean obviously you gotta
容易一点吧，我的意思是显然你必须
supply the issuer at the minimum you got
在您获得的最低限度内向发行人提供
to supply the client credentials and I'm
提供客户凭证，我
adding the scope so this is the minimal
添加范围，所以这是最小的
absolute minimal configuration let's
绝对最小的配置让我们
make sure this thing works I'm gonna
确保这个东西有效，我要
restart this
重新开始
let's a little let's log back in I'm
让我们再登录一下
gonna close this just to make sure I
要关闭它只是为了确保我
show you that we're logging back in all
告诉您我们正在重新登录所有
right there we go so we're still working
就在那边，所以我们还在工作
right okay so I'm logged in perfect
好的，所以我已完美登录
right so that was it so minimal
对，那是那么的最小
configuration dependencies open ID
配置依赖项打开ID
connect there we go
连接那里我们去
let's move on to the next thing the next
让我们继续下一件事
thing is okay so we've we set up with
事情还好，所以我们建立了
indication now we got these three
指示现在我们得到了这三个
microservices unsecured micro-services
微服务不安全的微服务
still right as you can see so we got to
如您所见，它仍然正确，所以我们必须
secure them so the first thing I'm going
保护他们，所以我要做的第一件事
to do is I'm gonna we're gonna work
我要做的是我们要去工作
backwards I'm gonna secure the resource
向后，我要保护资源
servers first right and then I'm gonna
服务器首先正确，然后我要
hit this endpoint the clients gonna try
达到这个目标，客户将尝试
to call obviously it's not passing an
打电话显然没有通过
access tool can there be a 401 that's
访问工具可以有一个401
the expectation right so let's configure
期望值，所以让我们进行配置
a resource server next let's configure
资源服务器接下来，我们来配置
now it's like any spring boot
现在就像任何 spring boot
application the first thing you do add
应用程序要做的第一件事
the dependencies right so let's do that
正确的依赖关系，让我们这样做
first we will we will work with
首先，我们将与之合作
microservice a and the spring boots
微服务A和春季靴
starter for for make this a little bit
的启动器，使这一点
bigger so everyone can see is is a lot
更大，所以每个人都可以看到很多
too resource server right and obviously
太资源服务器权利，显然
you got to use the the add the security
您必须使用添加安全性
starter as well alright so there you go
入门者也不错，所以你去了
they have that and now the next thing is
他们有那个，现在下一个是
properties again right once again I'm
属性再次正确我
gonna have to remove I disable the auto
要删除我禁用自动
configuration so I'm going to remove the
配置，所以我要删除
auto configuration of my spring root
自动配置我的spring root
annotation so that takes effect and then
注释，以便生效，然后
we're gonna go into we're gonna go into
我们要进入我们要进入
the properties and configure a resource
属性并配置资源
server alright so here we go so here's
服务器好，所以我们开始，这是
our here's our I'm gonna just actually
我们这里是我们我实际上
close some of these windows so we could
关闭其中一些窗口，以便我们可以
make this a little bit bigger so here we
使它更大一点，所以在这里我们
go so spring security ought to resource
去吧，春季安全应该有资源
server that's the base property path GWT
基本属性路径GWT的服务器
access token you know five two we're
您知道五两的访问令牌
going to have
将会有
Paik there right and then you can have
佩克在那里，然后你可以
your properties settings under there but
您的属性设置在那里
this is for GWT support and then I could
这是为了获得GWT支持，然后我可以
set up the jwk set your I let's take a
设置jwk设置你让我来
look at this what is this what's this
看看这是什么这是什么
gwk set your I if I go to the browser
gwk设置您的I（如果我转到浏览器）
here and type this in here we go right
在这里输入这里，我们走了
so this is basically what I was talking
所以这基本上就是我在说的
about earlier it's a it's a jwk JSON web
关于它是一个jwk JSON网站
key it's a JSON representation of a key
key这是密钥的JSON表示形式
that the provider uses to sign tokens
提供者用来签署令牌的
right in this case as you can see key
就在这种情况下，如您所见
type kty it's an RSA key all right so
输入kty这是一个RSA密钥，所以
it's a public key and this is ultimately
这是一个公钥，这最终是
what the client or the resource server
什么客户端或资源服务器
uses to get the public key and
用于获取公钥和
ultimately uses it to verify the
最终使用它来验证
signature right so there's the and there
正确的签名，所以在那里
could be more than one it's it's rooted
可能不止一个，因为它扎根了
at keys so there it's an array of keys
在键处，所以有一个键数组
but in this case we just got the one key
但是在这种情况下，我们只有一个钥匙
but there could be more than one and
但可能不止一个
we'll go back here now we also support
我们会回到这里现在我们也支持
we also support open academics discovery
我们还支持开放学者发现
on the resource server side so instead
在资源服务器端，所以
of specifying the the gwk set URI I'm
指定gwk设置URI的过程
just gonna specify the issue URI and
只需指定问题URI即可
it's going to discover the gwk say you
它会发现gwk说你
are your I just for the convenience and
是您，我只是为了方便起见，
I just prefer it that way so let's do
我只是喜欢那样，所以我们开始吧
that now let's start that up let's make
现在让我们开始吧，让我们
sure it's secured
确保它是安全的
the service for I'm just gonna go
我要去的服务
directly to the service and just see
直接到服务，然后看看
what happens here I think it's actually
我想这是真的
9,000 right this is what I got right
9,000对，这就是我正确的
this is what I expect 401 all right as
这是我期望401可以的
you can see here so that was pretty
你可以在这里看到所以很漂亮
quick right like literally dependencies
像字面上的依赖一样快速正确
properties and I'm secured right secure
财产，我有抵押
it as in at this V Fault configuration
与此V Fault配置中的一样
is when an access token comes in when a
是当访问令牌进入时
JWT comes in it will decode the GWT it
JWT进来它将解码GWT
will fetch the gwk right and resolve the
将正确获取gwk并解决
public key and then it will verify the
公钥，然后它将验证
signature and then the next thing it
签名，然后接下来的事情
will do is it will verify that it's not
会做的是会验证它不是
expired and then it'll also validate the
过期，然后它还将验证
issuer right that's the default
发行人权利是默认值
configuration and then it's it's
配置，然后是
authenticated right that's the
经过验证的权利
authorization role if you want to apply
授权角色（如果要申请）
finer grained author finer grained
细粒度的作者
authorization as in scope based
基于范围的授权
authorization which we are gonna do at
我们要做的授权
the end if we get to it we definitely
最后，如果我们做到这一点，我们肯定
want to do that but I'm just letting you
想这样做，但我只是让你
know right now that's the default
现在知道这是默认值
configuration okay so let's uh let's
配置好了，所以让我们吧
just what I'm gonna do I'm actually just
就是我要去做的
gonna I'm not going to bother repeating
我不会去重复
this this exercise for micro service B
此服务微服务B
because ultimately it's the same thing
因为最终是同一回事
right and we're just gonna cut to the
是的，我们将切入
chase and just check out this the
追逐，看看这个
specific commit and we are gonna see
具体的提交，我们将看到
what happens when we try to access
当我们尝试访问时会发生什么
access it through the app right now so
立即通过应用访问它，因此
at this very point I have microservice a
在这一点上我有微服务
and micro-service be secured right same
和微服务的权利相同
steps for both right let's try to access
正确的步骤，让我们尝试访问
the view app let's see what happens
查看应用程序，让我们看看会发生什么
let's make this a bit smaller okay
让我们把它缩小一点吧
that's that's what I expected I expected
那就是我所期望的
for one because obviously we haven't set
一个，因为显然我们还没有设定
it up we haven't set up the the client
我们还没有建立客户
to actually pass the access token right
实际传递访问令牌权限
and so that's what we're gonna do next
这就是我们接下来要做的
so right now on the UI app we're gonna
所以现在在UI应用程序上
set up a client that goes through the
建立一个通过
authorization code gram flow that
授权码克流程
obtains an access token that has the
获取具有以下内容的访问令牌：
capabilities or the authorities to call
能力或当局打电话
micro service a and micro service B so
微服务a和微服务B因此
let's do that next
接下来我们做
same procedure once again is
同样的程序是
dependencies okay our dependencies are
依赖我们的依赖是
there right because we already added it
那里正确，因为我们已经添加了它
the next thing we're gonna do is we are
接下来我们要做的是
gonna configure the OAuth client the new
要将新的OAuth客户端配置为
wallet client already have this existing
钱包客户已经有这个
one here and we're going to configure an
一个在这里，我们将配置一个
auth code one
验证码一
and there you go so I've given these
然后你走了，所以我给了这些
really generic names micro-service a
真正的通用名称微服务
micro service B client ABC Authority a
微服务B客户ABC授权a
Authority be right just it's so much
权威是对的
easier to track and just generic and
更容易追踪，而且通用
really the way the way I've named it is
确实是我命名的方式
micro service a authorizes Authority a
微服务a授权机构a
micro service B authorizes Authority B
微服务B授权机构B
so if you're if you you know after this
所以如果你知道的话
if you take a look at it that's how the
如果您看一下，那就是
naming came about so in this case client
命名就是这样，在这种情况下，客户端
ABC right has the capabilities are the
ABC权利具有的能力是
authorities for authority AC 8 BC
权威机构AC BC BC
therefore it could access micro service
因此它可以访问微服务
a micro serves B micro service C right
微型服务B微型服务C对
just just for a little bit of info on on
只是关于一些信息
the naming convention here and that's it
这里的命名约定就是这样
everything else is pretty standard from
其他一切都是很标准的
the previous the authorization code
先前的授权码
grant is by default because we're
授予是默认设置，因为我们
discovering by the issuer and we're just
由发行人发现，我们只是
requesting those three scopes so let's
请求这三个范围，让我们
do this so that's that's the first step
做到这一点，这就是第一步
now we have the client now we have to
现在我们有客户现在我们必须
use the clients right so the next thing
正确使用客户，所以接下来
we're gonna do is we're gonna actually
我们要做的是实际上
configure the web client integration so
配置Web客户端集成，以便
we have a we have pretty we have support
我们有一个我们有一个漂亮我们有支持
for web clients and I'll show you when I
适用于网络客户，我会在什么时候告诉你
get to this here and it's gonna make
在这里做到这一点，它将使
this a little bigger so I'll talk about
这个更大一点，我将谈论
this a bit so this is this is standard
这有点，这是标准
configuration for any web client that
任何Web客户端的配置
you're gonna use in any service this is
您将在任何服务中使用这是
pretty much like cut copy and paste so
非常像剪切复制粘贴
we have this this exchange filter
我们有这个交换过滤器
function servlet oath to authorize
功能servlet誓言授权
client exchange filter function super
客户端交换过滤功能超强
long name right but it makes sense right
长名称正确，但很有意义
it's it is an exchange filter function
这是一个交换过滤器功能
right it it requires an OAuth to
正确，它需要OAuth
authorize client and this is the
授权客户，这是
imperative version the servlets version
命令式版本servlets版本
right we also have the reactive version
对，我们也有反应式版本
prefix with server same name but server
服务器名称与服务器名称相同的前缀
now what does this do I mean an exchange
现在这是什么意思
filter function can tap into the request
过滤功能可以点击请求
pre-processing right of a web clients
Web客户的预处理权
and that's ultimately what we got to do
最终这就是我们要做的
right we got a we
对了，我们有一个
to put the access token as a bearer
将访问令牌作为承载
token in the authorization header we got
授权标头中的令牌
to tap into before that request is is
在该请求之前是
sent we got to add that header right so
发送，我们必须添加该标题正确
we're gonna we're plugging in with an
我们要插入一个
exchange filter function and this
交换过滤器功能和这个
specific exchange filter function needs
特定的交换过滤功能需求
an authorized clients right to get the
授权客户获得
access tool what's an authorized client
访问工具什么是授权客户
let's take a look at what an authorized
让我们来看看什么是授权
client is so an authorized client really
客户是真正的授权客户
it's an association class like when a
这是一个关联类，例如当
client gets authorized by a resource
客户获得资源授权
owner right we have a client right the
所有者权利，我们有客户权利
client registration the principal name
客户注册本名
that's the resource owner identifier and
这是资源所有者标识符，
then the result of that authorization is
那么授权的结果是
an access token and optionally a refresh
访问令牌和（可选）刷新
token right so when a client goes
令牌正确，所以当客户去时
through an authorization grant the end
通过授权授予结束
result is an authorized client and an
结果是获得授权的客户和
authorized client is stored in an
授权客户存储在
authorized client repository right so
授权的客户存储库就这样
that's what an authorized client is so
那就是授权客户
the exchange filter function it needs an
它需要一个交换过滤器功能
authorized client because that's where
授权的客户，因为那是
it gets the access token so we pass in
它获得了访问令牌，所以我们传入
the client registration repository the
客户端注册存储库
authorized client repository so it knows
授权的客户端存储库，以便知道
how to do its thing
怎么做
right and that's pretty much it and then
对，就是这样，然后
so we create an instance of this and
所以我们创建了一个实例
then we apply it as you see this one
然后我们将其应用于您所看到的这一点
line here we apply it to the Builder and
在这里，我们将其应用于生成器
ultimately what this does is it adds it
最终这是将其添加
as exchange filter function and it has
作为交换过滤器功能，它具有
quite a few different capabilities I
我有很多不同的能力
mean a couple of them is if if an access
意思是如果访问
token is expired it will refresh it
令牌已过期，它将刷新它
right it will refresh it for an
对的它将刷新它
authorization code client if there's a
授权码客户端（如果有）
refresh token for a client credentials
刷新客户端凭证的令牌
client if the access token is expired it
客户端（如果访问令牌已过期）
will just call the token endpoint
只会调用令牌端点
ultimately renewing the access token
最终更新访问令牌
right so these are the capabilities
对，所以这些就是功能
built into it and this is ultimately
内置其中，这最终是
where other grand types are going to be
其他盛大类型将在哪里
added for five two were planning for
为五个增加了两个
resource Alando password and we're gonna
资源Alando密码，我们将
definitely try to get into the GWT
一定要尝试加入GWT
barrier grant as well so this is the web
障碍补助金，所以这是网络
client configuration so now that I've
客户端配置，现在我已经
configured my client my web client now
现在将我的客户端配置为我的Web客户端
got to use this web client so let's take
必须使用此网络客户端，所以让我们
a look at what does that take I'm gonna
看看我要怎么办
go to I'm gonna go to that main
去我要去那个主要的
controller that gets called when I click
单击时调用的控制器
that link right and I'm gonna add I mean
该链接正确，我要添加的意思是
there's a few different ways and I'm
有几种不同的方式，我
gonna show the this the annotation way
将显示此注释方式
of authorizing a client so this this
授权客户的方法
annotation this handler method argument
注释此处理程序方法参数
resolver registered a lot to authorize
解析器注册了很多授权
clients right I specify the the
客户对，我指定了
registration ID client ABC because
注册ID客户ABC，因为
that's what I've configured that's the
这就是我配置的
registration ID that's the specific
特定的注册ID
client that I want to resolve and
我要解决的客户
ultimately use in a protected resource
最终在受保护的资源中使用
request
请求
so this annotation what it ultimately
所以这个注释到底是什么
does is I mean it resolves an authorized
是不是我的意思是它解决了授权问题
client in a nutshell but if the client
简而言之，如果客户
is not authorized then it triggers the
未经授权，则触发
authorization grant so in this case it's
授权授予，因此在这种情况下
an authorization code grant so it
授权码授予，因此
triggers that flow right and eventually
触发正确的流动并最终
it gets redirected back to this back to
它被重定向回此
this some endpoint because this is the
这个端点，因为这是
redirect URI and then it's able to
重定向URI，然后就可以
resolve it because at that plant it's in
解决它，因为在那家工厂
the authorized client repository now I
现在授权的客户资料库I
have my authorized clients therefore you
有我的授权客户，所以你
know I could get the access token or the
知道我可以获取访问令牌或
web client could that get the access
网络客户端可以获取访问权限
token now I gotta use it right so the
令牌现在我要正确使用，所以
next thing I'm going to do is you know
接下来我要做的是你知道
I'm just passing in all into here I'm
我只是把所有的东西都传到这里
just gonna add this into these methods
只需将其添加到这些方法中
and we're gonna go straight to the
我们将直接去
actual you know where it's set so right
实际上，您知道它的设置正确
here web clients right this is the main
这里的网络客户对，这是主要的
line so web client has the capabilities
行，因此Web客户端具有功能
of adding requests request attributes
请求添加请求属性
which is very nice rest template didn't
这是非常好的休息模板没有
have that which which was yeah too bad
有那是太糟糕了
but either way so what ultimately what
但无论哪种方式，最终会怎样
what this is happening hey what's
这是怎么回事
happening here is this is to authorize
发生在这里是为了授权
client static method returns a consumer
客户端静态方法返回使用者
that ultimately adds the authorize
最终增加了授权
client into a request attribute so when
客户进入请求属性，所以当
the exchange filter function get is hit
交换过滤器功能get被点击
in the filter before the request is
在过滤条件之前
initiated it knows where to find the
启动它知道在哪里可以找到
authorize client and therefore an
授权客户，因此
were to get the access token and
将获得访问令牌，并
therefore it adds the header right so
因此它正确添加了标题
that's basically the next step you got
那基本上就是你下一步
to do for the web client integration so
为Web客户端集成做的事情
basically I think I think that's pretty
基本上我认为我认为这很漂亮
much it you got the web client
您获得了Web客户端
configuration you configure the client
您配置客户端的配置
the web client configuration which is
Web客户端配置
standard and then resolve it through the
标准，然后通过
handler method argument solver and then
处理程序方法参数求解器，然后
use it in the web client so based on
在网络客户端中使用它，因此基于
this we're gonna start this we're gonna
这个我们要开始这个我们要
restart UI app now and then we're gonna
现在重新启动UI应用程序，然后我们将
there we go right so the handler method
那里我们走对了，所以处理程序方法
the registered authorized client like I
我这样的注册授权客户
mentioned it triggers the authorization
提到触发授权
because it couldn't resolve the
因为它无法解决
authorized client redirecting back to
授权客户端重定向回
the provider as you can see when I
如我所见，提供者
configured my client I configured it to
配置我的客户端，我将其配置为
request these three scopes because I
请求这三个范围，因为我
want to be able to call all three
希望能够呼叫所有三个
micro-services and they're there you see
微服务，它们在那里
it D la access for all these three
这三个都可以访问
authorities I'm gonna click authorize
我要点击授权
and there we go right so now we have
然后我们就走了，所以现在我们有了
information as you can see here UI app
您可以在此处看到的信息UI应用程序
call service say I've highlighted
呼叫服务说我已突出显示
specifically the JSON web token
特别是JSON网络令牌
identifier as you can see it's the same
如您所见，标识符是相同的
one right the authorities yeah one thing
一件事，当局是一件事
to note here you'll see the authorities
在这里注意，您会看到当局
their scope underscore so a resource
它们的范围强调了资源
server by default will inspect the GWT
默认情况下，服务器将检查GWT
and a look at this try to find a scope
看看这个尝试找到一个范围
plan because it's you know it's optional
计划，因为这是您知道的可选项目
it's not necessarily there but if it
它不一定在那里，但如果有的话
finds a scope claim whether its scope or
查找范围声明，无论其范围还是
SCP then what it'll do it will basically
SCP，然后它会做什么基本上
append scope and then add those as
追加范围，然后将其添加为
granted authorities to the
授权给
authentication instance the GWT
GWT认证实例
authentication instance in case you're
身份验证实例，以防万一
wondering what that scope prefix there
想知道那个范围前缀在那里
is and then the subject that's that's me
是然后主题就是我
I own the token right I authorize a
我拥有令牌权，我授权了
client the clients acting on my behalf
客户代我行事的客户
to access my resources and but the
访问我的资源，但是
audience is the client right so as you
听众是客户的权利，就像你一样
can see we got some information here now
可以看到我们现在在这里获得了一些信息
but we don't have any information with
但是我们没有任何信息
service B to Service Eve so that's our
服务B到服务前夕，这就是我们的服务
next step and I'm just doing a time
下一步，我只是在做一段时间
check and I got about 15 minutes so I'm
检查，我大约有15分钟，所以我
going to try to
将尝试
expedite this so the next thing we got
加快这一步，所以接下来的事情
to do what I'm going to do next actually
去做我接下来要做的事
is we didn't have microservice C secured
我们没有安全的微服务C
so I'm just going to check that out so
所以我要检查一下
now at this very point we have all three
现在，在这一点上，我们所有三个
services secured right I'm just going to
服务保证正确，我正要去
restart this and now we're gonna set up
重新开始，现在我们要设置
we're gonna set up the client on micro
我们将在微型计算机上设置客户
service be to call micro service see
服务叫微服务见
right but this time we're gonna you know
对，但是这次我们要你知道
use the client credentials grant and why
使用客户端凭据授予以及为什么
am i using the client credentials grant
我在使用客户凭证授予吗
why am I not using an authorization code
为什么我不使用授权码
why am I not using maybe a token
为什么我不使用令牌
exchange pattern I mean in the end you
交换方式我的意思是最后你
know for the authorization code grant
知道授权码的授予
flow there's a there's a read there's a
流有一个有读有一个
user there's a resource owner
用户有一个资源所有者
authorizing a client the user owns that
授权用户拥有的客户
token there's user context information
令牌中有用户上下文信息
in that token so you would use that
在那个令牌，所以你会用那个
grant in I'll use an example like an
授予，我将使用一个示例
e-commerce site you know I got a
您知道我有一个电子商务网站
shopping cart right I'm buying some
购物车对，我要买一些
products right
产品权
obviously there's user information
显然有用户信息
attached to the shopping cart attached
附在购物车上
to the order but products like an
订单但产品像
inventory service user doesn't own that
广告资源服务用户不拥有该资源
you don't need user context information
您不需要用户上下文信息
that's a system service right so client
这是系统服务，因此客户端
credentials is perfect candidate for
凭据是完美的候选人
that kind of a call so imagine micro
这样的电话，所以想像微
service be our sorry
服务是我们的遗憾
imagine micro service see in inventory
想象微服务看到库存
check service that's when you would use
检查您将要使用的服务
a client credentials guy you don't need
您不需要的客户凭证人
user context information it's the system
用户上下文信息就是系统
service right so let's let's let's set
服务正确，所以让我们让我们设置
that up right now let's set that client
现在设置我们的客户端
up so we're gonna go to
起来，所以我们要去
excuse me now we have we've already set
对不起，现在我们已经设置好了
up our dependencies right for we've got
建立我们的依赖关系
the resource serving clients so that's
服务客户的资源，因此
already done and now the next thing is
已经完成，现在下一步
yeah we've got actually got a disable
是的，我们实际上有一个残疾
the auto configuration so I'm going to
自动配置，所以我要
go to that yeah actually I already did
去，是的，实际上我已经做了
that yeah on the previous one and now
是的，在上一个和现在
we're going to set up the new clients
我们将要建立新的客户
okay so here we have client C client
好的，所以这里有客户端C客户端
credentials we're just gonna request one
我们只是要一个凭证
Authority you know all very similar the
权威大家都知道非常相似的
only difference here really is the
唯一的区别是
authorization grant and they'll redirect
授权授予，他们将重定向
to your I but everything else status quo
对你我，但其他一切
so so I've set up my client now I gotta
所以现在我已经建立了我的客户
use it in the same procedure now I'm
我现在以相同的程序使用它
gonna go and set up my web client
要去建立我的网络客户端
configuration let's go to your web
配置让我们进入您的网站
client here remove this once again like
客户在这里再次删除此喜欢
I said it's if the the same
我说是一样的
configuration applies right there we go
配置就在那里
and and now we got a use right we got to
现在我们有了使用权
use the authorize client and we're gonna
使用授权客户，我们将
go to the the the handler or without the
去处理程序或没有
controller so let's go to micro service
控制器，让我们进入微服务
be service which is right here I'm just
服务，就在这里，我只是
gonna actually close these windows
实际上要关闭这些窗口
because things are getting a little bit
因为事情有点
busy and then we're gonna do the same
忙，然后我们要做同样的事情
thing we're gonna we're gonna resolve
我们要解决的事情
and this is client C alright cuz that's
这是客户C好吧，因为
what I just configured client C you'll
我刚刚配置的客户端C，您将
notice there the GWT GWT authentication
注意那里的GWT GWT身份验证
token if you're not familiar you could
如果您不熟悉，可以
resolve the authentication and you could
解决身份验证，您可以
have access to the JWT directly if you
如果您可以直接访问JWT
needed it if you're not aware of that so
如果您不知道的话就需要它
here we have the authorized clients i'm
在这里，我们有授权的客户
resolving it and then i'm gonna use it
解决它，然后我要使用它
alright so seam seam seam procedure
好吧，接缝，接缝，接缝程序
really here as well like the really you
真的在这里以及真的在你
know compared to the the client on
知道与客户相比
microphone the UI app and a client on on
麦克风UI应用程序并打开客户端
my cursors be everything's really the
我的游标是真的
same the only difference is the client
唯一的不同是客户
properties right the authorization grant
产权授权书
there's no redirect everything else same
没有重定向其他所有相同的东西
right consistent right now the only
现在唯一的一致
thing i wanted to point out though is if
我想指出的是
i go back to the application properties
我回到应用程序属性
here so we have a resource server acting
在这里，所以我们有一个资源服务器
as a client as well and the default
作为客户，默认
configuration
组态
for spring boot auto-configuration that
用于Spring Boot自动配置
is is for all of client functionality it
是用于所有客户端功能的
will enable us to log in open ID connect
将使我们能够登录开放ID连接
and a lot to clients right so I don't
对客户来说很多，所以我不
want that right I don't I don't want to
想要那个权利，我不，我不想
enable open ID Connect so I'm gonna
启用开放ID Connect，这样我就可以
override spring boots Auto configuration
覆盖弹簧靴自动配置
so I got to specify my own custom
所以我必须指定自己的习惯
configuration so let's let's do that
配置，让我们开始吧
okay we'll add a resource or config
好吧，我们将添加资源或配置
extend that and we'll do our maple web
扩展它，我们将做我们的枫叶网
security and let's let's just get the
安全性，让我们开始吧
our template out here and there we go
我们的模板随处可见
right so we've enabled resource server
对的，所以我们启用了资源服务器
they're gonna make this a little bit
他们会做一点
bigger so ever we can see so there's a
更大，所以我们可以看到所以有一个
there's our custom configuration which
有我们的自定义配置
is pretty much exactly what spring boot
几乎就是 spring boot
would do as well other than - - oauth2
除了-之外，oauth2也会做得很好
login but this is exactly what spring
登录，但这正是春天
spring boot would do but we want to
春季靴会做，但我们想
override it remove all to login because
覆盖它删除所有要登录，因为
we don't want that right so there we go
我们不想那样做，所以我们去了
let's start up let's restart
让我们启动让我们重新启动
micro-service b and microservice see I
微服务b和微服务请参阅I
already did start but I'll try it again
已经开始，但我会再试一次
just to be sure and at this point I
只是为了确定，在这一点上我
should be able to see all three flows
应该能够看到所有三个流程
and all three pieces of data between the
和之间的所有三个数据
three interactions now let's take a look
现在我们来看看三种互动
and there we go right as you can see
如您所见，我们就在那里
here the GTI is different right because
这里的GTI是不同的权利，因为
we use the client credentials grand and
我们使用客户凭证grand和
you can see that the authorities here
您可以看到这里的当局
scope Authority see and the big
范围权威看到和大
difference here is the subject right
这里的区别是主题权利
who's the owner of this access token
谁是此访问令牌的所有者
well it's the client it's not me right
好吧，那是客户，这不是我的权利
because I use the client credentials
因为我使用客户端凭据
grants this is a systems level service
授予这是系统级别的服务
the inventory service the client owns
客户拥有的库存服务
the token the client makes the call
客户拨打电话的令牌
right so there we go so that's that's
对，所以我们走了，那就是
pretty much it that's like three micro
差不多就是三个微
services secured you know not
服务安全，你不知道
fine-grained authorization we're gonna
细粒度的授权，我们要
do that next because we actually got
接下来，因为我们实际上得到了
time which is great and we've set up
很棒的时间，我们已经建立了
open ID connect so now we've completely
开放的ID连接，所以现在我们已经完全
secured our architecture right now let's
立即保护我们的架构，让我们
set up finer grain authorization because
设置更好的谷物授权，因为
ultimately you know micro service a
最终您知道微服务
should authorize only on access tokens
应该只授权访问令牌
that have scope a write or scope
具有范围的写入或范围
Authority a and microservice B scope
权限A和微服务B范围
Authority B and so forth so let's let's
权限B等，让我们开始吧
set that up what does that take let's
设置那需要做什么，让我们
let's just do it for one will do for a
让我们做一个就做
for micro service a and we'll go to my
对于微服务a，我们将去我的
cursor assay here
光标分析
actually no will do no make service
其实没有就不会提供服务
because I have a custom configuration
因为我有一个自定义配置
there because we need to have a custom
在那里，因为我们需要一个习惯
configuration obviously for to set that
配置显然是为了设置
up so we're going to resource server a
起来，所以我们要去资源服务器
and I will remove this and then we'll do
我将删除它，然后我们将
this alright so service B so here we go
这样很好，服务B，所以我们开始
here we have it right
在这里我们有权利
we're authorizing on anything service B
我们正在授权任何服务B
and has authority scope Authority B now
并且现在具有权限范围B
let's actually just let's put X in there
让我们把X放进去
right and restart and see what happens
正确并重新启动，看看会发生什么
because Vic's expectation would be
因为维克的期望是
forbidden right because the ax token
禁止的权利，因为斧头令牌
that's coming in here has Authority
即将到来的权限
Authority B Authority C does not have a
机构B机构C没有
throw
扔
X right so the resource server should
X正确，因此资源服务器应该
not allow the request to go through and
不允许请求通过
let's just confirm that all right there
让我们确认一下
we go so we got 403 forbidden all right
我们去，所以我们有403禁止吧
that's the expectation right so we've
那是期望值，所以我们已经
set up find a green authorization now
设置现在查找绿色授权
we're gonna change this back to B right
我们要把它改回B对
we will restart this and we will ensure
我们将重新启动，并确保
that things are still working and they
事情还在进行，他们
are alright there we go
好的，我们去了
now I encourage you I encourage you to
现在我鼓励你我鼓励你
take a look at this sample and give me
看看这个样品，给我
some feedback because the whole goal of
一些反馈，因为整个目标
this sample is because I'm getting a lot
这个例子是因为我有很多
of I get a lot of questions right how do
我有很多问题，正确的做法
you piece everything together I mean
你把所有东西拼凑起来
it's easy to have one sample a basic
一个基本的样本很容易
sample setting up open ID Connect or one
样本设置开放式ID Connect或一个
resource server with one client big deal
一个客户端的资源服务器大交易
this is not real world right so I want
这不是现实世界，所以我想要
more of an advanced sample that's more
更多高级样本，更多
real-world that demonstrates common
展示共同点的真实世界
patterns right you know I have the token
模式，你知道我有令牌
exchange pattern why would you use that
交换模式你为什么要使用那个
pattern I mean look at look at this here
模式我的意思是看这里
right I have this token here getting
对，我在这里有这个令牌
passed with three scopes right Authority
通过三个范围的权利机构
Authority B Authority C right why would
管理局B管理局C对，为什么会
I pass an access token to a resource
我将访问令牌传递给资源
server that doesn't authorize on a
没有授权的服务器
specific scope like for example
特定范围，例如
microcircuits is only concerned about
微电路只在乎
Authority it doesn't care about
不在乎的权威
Authority B right so ultimately this
管理局B对，所以最终
access token has a higher level of
访问令牌的级别更高
privileges right which means if it gets
特权权利，这意味着如果获得
leaked then I have higher access right I
泄漏然后我有更高的访问权限
could access all three services now if I
如果我现在可以访问所有三个服务
only had an access token that was you
只有一个访问令牌是你
know that only had authority to access a
知道只有权限才能访问
specific service the minimal privileges
特定服务的最小特权
for example an access token that just
例如一个访问令牌
had well just like the client
就像客户一样
densha's right the Klang credentials has
densha的巴生凭证具有的权利
one Authority that's a good one
一个权威就是一个好权威
right because if this gets leaked well
对，因为如果泄漏得很好
you could only access the inventory
您只能访问库存
service that's it right if the other
服务是对的，如果其他
access token gets leaked then obviously
访问令牌被泄漏然后很明显
I could access more and do more damage
我可以访问更多并造成更多损失
right that's what I like about the this
对，这就是我喜欢的
token exchange pattern and it's one of
令牌交换模式，它是其中之一
the flows in here obviously I can't get
显然这里的人流我听不到
to it today so I'll just talk about it
今天就来讨论一下
is microservice be right we'll receive
微服务是正确的，我们会收到
an access token with three three three
具有三个三三的访问令牌
scopes associated to it ideally what I
与它相关的范围理想地是我
would like to do to keep security even
甚至想保持安全
tighter is exchange that token and
更紧密地交换令牌和
downgrade the Scopes the access token or
降级范围访问令牌或
the JWT looks pretty much the same the
JWT看起来几乎一样
only difference is the Scopes have been
唯一的区别是范围已经
downgraded to only the scope that the
降级到仅
the destination resource server
目标资源服务器
authorizes on so I would use this token
授权，因此我将使用此令牌
exchange pattern which is which is the
交换模式是
g-dub one of them is is a GWT barrier
g-dub其中之一是GWT障碍
grants which we're planning and getting
我们正在计划和获得的赠款
into five to to pass the access token
分为五个以传递访问令牌
that I received for another access token
我收到的另一个访问令牌
exchange it for lesser scopes right and
交换它为较小的范围权利和
then call microservice keys and see and
然后调用微服务密钥并查看和
and that's a that's a good one right I
那是一个很好的权利，我
like that one because you're keeping
喜欢那个，因为你一直在
security tight right if that gets leaked
如果泄漏，则安全性严格
once again you could only access that
再一次，你只能访问那个
one service right and that's why the
一种服务权，这就是为什么
token relay pattern and that's the other
令牌中继模式，这就是另一个
flow that I have there you got to be
我必须在那里的流动
very careful with that one especially
特别注意那个
yeah like I know it's very convenient to
是的，就像我知道这很方便
set up a client that has you know five
建立一个你知道五个的客户
scopes ten scopes but we need to do that
范围十个范围，但我们需要这样做
you you have an access token that has a
您有一个访问令牌，其中包含
lot of power right and it's convenient
强大的功能，方便
yes and then you just relay it to all
是的，然后您将其转发给所有人
services because all of them you know
服务，因为您都知道
we'll take it instead of setting up
我们将采用它而不是设置
clients within the services that you
您所提供服务中的客户
know exchange it for more downgraded
知道将它换成更多降级的东西
skills but you got to be very careful
技巧，但是你要非常小心
using token relay patterns it's
使用令牌中继模式
definitely a pattern I wouldn't
绝对是我不会的模式
recommend unless it's behind the
除非它在后面
firewall in tight security quarters and
安全区域内的防火墙和
you know so forth but even then yeah you
你知道这样，但即使如此，你
just got to be careful I just wanted to
只是要小心，我只是想
like kind of really mention that from a
就像真的从
high level but you feel free
高水平，但你感到自由
- - check out those other two flows and
--检查另外两个流程和
I made it just in time I can't believe
我做到了我不敢相信的时间
it
它
thank you very much there's a link to
非常感谢你有一个链接
the repo there so yeah thank you
那里的回购所以是的，谢谢
[Music]
[音乐]